filmfreeway.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy - FilmFreeway

Last updated: May 21, 2018

**About FilmFreeway:**

Welcome to FilmFreeway. FilmFreeway makes it easy to discover, submit, and get tickets to thousands of film festivals, screenplay contests, music contests and photography contests all over the world. We do this through our websites and domains, the services available on or through our websites and domains or otherwise provided by us, and the software available on or through our websites and domains or otherwise provided by us (including our mobile applications) (collectively, the "Services").

**Our Policy:**

This Privacy Policy sets forth our policy with respect to information, including personally identifiable information ("Personal Data"), that is collected from users of and/or visitors to the Services (including through those users' and visitors' agents) ("you" or "your"), including (i) registered users who are film festivals, events, and contests ("Festivals"), (ii) users who want to view information about or submit their work to events (whether free or paid) listed by Festivals on the Services ("Filmmakers"), and (iii) other Non-Festival users or visitors to the Services ("other Non-Festivals").

We take the privacy of your Personal Data and other information seriously. Because of that, we have created this Privacy Policy. Please read this Privacy Policy as it includes important information regarding your Personal Data and other information.

Except as otherwise noted in this Privacy Policy, FilmFreeway is a data controller (as that term is used under the ([ EU General Data Protection Regulation](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=EN)) (“GDPR”), which means that we decide how and why the information you provide to us is processed. Contact details are provided below. This Policy may be amended or updated from time to time to reflect changes in our practices with respect to the Processing of your information, or changes in applicable law. We encourage you to read this Policy carefully, and to regularly check this page to review any changes we might make.

If you have any questions or concerns, please do not hesitate to contact us by using the following link: https://filmfreeway.com/pages/contact

**CONSENT:**

**By using the Services or allowing someone to use the Services on your behalf, you are consenting to our collection, use, disclosure, transfer and storage in accordance with this Privacy Policy of any Personal Data or other information received by us as a result of such use.**

**Information We Collect:**

When you interact with us through the Services, we may collect Personal Data and other information from you, as further described below:

**1\. Personal Data:**

**Festivals** : We collect Personal Data from you when you voluntarily provide such information to the Services, such as when you register for access to the Services as a Festival. The Personal Data we may collect includes without limitation your name, address, email address and other personally identifiable information. In addition, if you use our payment processing services, we will collect financial information from you (e.g., your bank account information or an address to send checks) as necessary to facilitate payments and information required for tax purposes (e.g., your taxpayer identification number).

**Filmmakers and other Non-Festivals** : We collect Personal Data from you when you voluntarily provide such information to the Services, such as when you register for access to the Services (whether as a Festival or otherwise), submit to an film festival as a Filmmaker or use certain parts of the Services. The Personal Data we may collect includes without limitation your name, address, email address, zip code and other personally identifiable information. In addition, Festivals can set up event registration pages to collect virtually any information from Filmmakers in connection with submission to a Festival's event listed on the Services. If a Filmmaker voluntarily provides that information in connection with submission to an event or otherwise, it will be available to us and will be held by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy. In addition, such information will be delivered to the Festival in accordance with "Our Disclosure of Information That We Collect: Festivals" below.

**Sensitive Personal Data** : We do not collect or otherwise Process Personal Information about race or ethnicity, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, physical or mental health, sexual life, any actual or alleged criminal offences or penalties, or any other information that may be deemed to be sensitive under GDPR (collectively, “Sensitive Personal Information”) in the ordinary course of our business. Where it becomes necessary to Process Sensitive Personal Information under GDPR, we would rely on one of the following legal bases: Compliance with applicable law: We may Process your Sensitive Personal Information where the Processing is required or permitted by applicable law; Detection and prevention of crime: We may Process your Sensitive Personal Information where the Processing is necessary for the detection or prevention of crime (including the prevention of fraud); Establishment, exercise or defense of legal rights: We may Process your Sensitive Personal Information where the Processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal rights; or Consent: We may Process your Sensitive Personal Information where we have, in accordance with applicable law, obtained your prior, express consent prior to Processing your Sensitive Personal Information.

**Privacy Policy Links** : We make an effort to provide a link to this Privacy Policy in the footer of every page on our websites, including those pages on which Personal Data is collected, and to make it available in all of our software.

**2\. Non-Personal Data:**

**Non-Identifiable Data** : When you interact with the Services, we collect certain personally non-identifiable information ("Non-Personal Data"). The Non-Personal Data we collect includes without limitation Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, Internet browser type, other characteristics of your device and software, domain names of your Internet Service Provider, your approximate geographic location, a record of your usage of the Services, the time of your usage and aggregated Personal Data that cannot be used to specifically identify you. Such information, which is collected passively using various technologies, cannot, in and of itself, be used to specifically identify you. We also collect Non-Personal Data (including, without limitation, of the type set forth above) from third parties. The information we collect from third parties may be combined with the information we collect.

**Aggregated Personal Data** : In an ongoing effort to better understand and serve the users of the Services, we often conduct research on our customer demographics, interests and behavior based on Personal Data and other information that we have collected. This research may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate basis and this aggregate information does not identify you personally and therefore is considered and treated as Non-Personal Data under this Privacy Policy.

**3\. Cookies, Pixels Tags, Local Shared Objects, Web Storage and Similar Technologies:**

Please refer to our Cookie Policy, which is hereby incorporated by reference into this Privacy Policy, for more information about our use of these technologies.

**Our Use of Information That We Collect:**

**1\. Personal Data:**

We use the Personal Data we collect in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. We may use the Personal Data as follows:

**Specific Reason** : If you provide Personal Data for a certain reason, we may use the Personal Data in connection with the reason for which it was provided. For instance, if you contact us by e-mail, we will use the Personal Data you provide to answer your question or resolve your problem and will respond to the email address from which the contact came.

**Access and Use** : If you provide Personal Data in order to obtain access to or use of the Services or any functionality thereof, we will use your Personal Data to provide you with access to or use of the Services or functionality and to monitor your use of such Services or functionality.

**Internal Business Purposes** : We may use your Personal Data for internal business purposes including without limitation to help us improve the content and functionality of the Services, to better understand our users, to improve the Services, to protect against, identify or address wrongdoing, to enforce our Terms of Service, to manage your account and provide you with customer service, and to generally manage the Services and our business.

**Marketing** : We may use your Personal Data to contact you in the future for our marketing and advertising purposes, including without limitation to inform you about services or events we believe might be of interest to you, to develop promotional or marketing materials and provide those materials to you, and to display content and advertising on or off the Services that we believe might be of relevance to you. In particular, Festivals should note that we may use information we receive or collect regarding Filmmakers (including without limitation via an Festival's event submission page) in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy, including in the manner set forth above.

**Festival Emails** : We allow Festivals to use our email system to contact Filmmakers for their current and past events, so you may receive emails from our system that originate with such Festivals.

If we intend to use any Personal Data in any manner that is not consistent with this Privacy Policy, you will be informed of such anticipated use prior to or at the time at which the Personal Data is collected or we will obtain your consent subsequent to such collection but prior to such use.

**2\. Non-Personal Data:**

Because Non-Personal Data cannot be used to personally identify you, we may use such information for any lawful purpose.

**Our Disclosure of Information That We Collect:**

**1\. Personal Data:**

We are not in the business of selling your Personal Data. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you. Therefore, we will not sell or share your Personal Data to third parties, including third party advertisers. There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may disclose, transfer or share your Personal Data with certain third parties as set forth below:

**Business Transfers** : As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, Personal Data may be part of the transferred assets. You acknowledge and agree that any successor to or acquirer of FilmFreeway (or its assets) will continue to have the right to use your Personal Data and other information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**Subsidiaries and Affiliates** : We may also share your Personal Data with our subsidiaries and/or affiliates for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. Our subsidiaries and affiliates will be bound to maintain that Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Agents, Consultants and Related Third Parties** : We, like many businesses, sometimes engage other companies to perform certain business-related functions. Examples of such functions include mailing information, fraud prevention, maintaining databases and processing payments. When we engage another company to perform such functions, we may provide them with information, including Personal Data, in connection with their performance of such functions.

**Festivals** : When you submit to Festival on the Services, you consent to our providing your Personal Data to the Festivals, if applicable. These Festivals are not bound to treat your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You agree that we are not responsible for the actions of these Festivals with respect to your Personal Data. It is important that you review the applicable policies of the Festivals of an event (and the related fundraising page, if applicable) before providing Personal Data or other information in connection with that event or related fundraising page.

**Facebook and Other Third Party Connections** : You can connect your FilmFreeway account to your accounts on third party services like Facebook, in which case we may collect, use, disclose, transfer and store information relating to your account with such third party services in accordance with this Privacy Policy. For example, if you connect with Facebook, we store your Facebook ID, first name, last name, email and profile picture and use them to connect with your Facebook account to provide certain functionality on the Services.

**Legal Requirements** : We may disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law (including, without limitation responding to a subpoena or request from law enforcement, court or government agency) or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary (i) to comply with a legal obligation, (ii) to protect or defend our rights, interests or property or that of third parties, (iii) to prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with the Services, (iv) to act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Services or the public, or (v) to protect against legal liability.

**2\. Non-Personal Data:**

Because Non-Personal Data cannot be used to personally identify you, we may disclose, transfer or share Non-Personal Data for any lawful purpose.

**Your Choices:**

You have several choices available when it comes to your Personal Data:

**Limit the Personal Data You Provide** : You can use the Services without providing any Personal Data or with limiting the Personal Data you provide. If you choose not to provide any Personal Data or limit the Personal Data you provide, you may not be able to use certain functionality of the Services. For instance, in order to open an account, submit or receive submissions, your name and email address will be required.

**Opt Out** : You can "opt out" of receiving FilmFreeway newsletter emails by logging in, clicking on "Account" and following the instructions to "Email Preferences." You may modify your choices at any time in your FilmFreeway account. In the event a Festival uses our system to email you, you will be able to "opt out" of receiving those communications as well. Please note that if you unsubscribe from receiving a particular Festival's emails, you will no longer receive emails from the particular Festival that are sent through our system (but you may still receive emails sent by that Festival through means other than our system), however, you will still receive FilmFreeway communications and communications from other Festivals whose events you have submitted to or who have otherwise obtained your email address. Likewise, if you unsubscribe from our communications you will continue to receive communications from Festivals. So you may have to unsubscribe from multiple emails before you stop receiving all communications. You can also unsubscribe from receiving all Festival emails sent through our system. It may take up to 24 hours for us to process an unsubscribe request. Note that you cannot unsubscribe from update communications about the Services. You can stop receiving Service communications only by contacting us at https://filmfreeway.com/pages/contact and closing your account. By electing to stop receiving all communications from us or through our system you will no longer receive any updates on your account or on events you have submitted to or have previously attended, including communications regarding refunds. We do not recommend that you do this unless you plan to no longer use the Services, are not currently registered for an event, are not currently organizing an event and will have no need to receive further communications from us or through our system. Even after you opt out of all communications, we will retain your Personal Data and Non-Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy, however, we will no longer use it to contact you. However, Festivals who have received your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy may still use that Personal Data to contact you in accordance with their own privacy policies, but they may not use our system to do so.

**Do Not Track** : We currently do not participate in any "Do Not Track" frameworks that would allow us to respond to signals or other mechanisms from you regarding the collection of your Personal Data.

**Exclusions:**

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any Personal Data collected by us other than Personal Data collected through the Services. This Privacy Policy shall not apply to any unsolicited information you provide to us or another user or visitor through the Services or through any other means. This includes, but is not limited to, information posted to any public areas of the Services, such as bulletin boards, any ideas for new products or modifications to existing products, claim or demand letters, and other unsolicited submissions (collectively, "Unsolicited Information"). All Unsolicited Information shall be deemed to be non-confidential and we shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose, distribute and exploit such Unsolicited Information without limitation or attribution.

**Children:**

We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any Personal Data through the Services. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children's Internet usage and to help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children never to provide Personal Data through the Services without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided Personal Data to us through the Services, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases.

**Links to Other Web Sites:**

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Services. The Services may contain links to other websites not operated or controlled by us (the "Third Party Sites"). The policies and procedures we described here do not apply to the Third Party Sites. The links from the Services do not imply that we endorse or have reviewed the Third Party Sites. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy policies.

**Storage and Security:**

We may store Personal Data itself or such information may be included in databases owned and maintained by our affiliates, agents or service providers. We take what we believe to be reasonable steps to protect the Personal Data provided via the Services from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, inadvertent disclosure, alteration, and destruction. However, no Internet or e-mail transmission is ever fully secure or error free. In particular, e-mail sent to or from the Services may not be secure. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via e-mail. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any Personal Data via the Internet.

**International Privacy Laws:**

If you are visiting our website or using one of our software applications from outside the Canada, please be aware that you are sending information (including Personal Data) to Canada where our servers are located. We will hold and process your Personal Data and Non-Personal Data in accordance with privacy laws in the Canada and this Privacy Policy. Please note that privacy laws in the Canada may not be the same as, and in some cases may be less protective than, the privacy laws in your country.

**EU Residents:**

GDPR provides certain rights for EU residents. You may decline to share certain information with us, in which case we may not be able to provide some of the features and functionality of the Services. These rights include, in accordance with applicable law, the right to object to or request the restriction of processing of your information, and to request access to, rectification, erasure and portability of your own information. Where we process your information on the basis of your consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent (noting that such withdrawal does not affect the lawfulness of any Processing performed prior to the date on which we receive notice of such withdrawal, and does not prevent the Processing of your Personal Information in reliance upon any other available legal bases). Requests should be submitted by contacting us (using the contact instructions below). If you are an EU resident and have any unresolved privacy concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily after contacting us, you have the right to contact the appropriate EU Supervisory Authority and lodge a complaint.

If you are an EU resident, you may have certain rights including: the right not to provide your Personal Information to us; the right of access to your Personal Information; the right to request rectification of inaccuracies; the right to request the erasure, or restriction of Processing, of your Personal Information; the right to object to the Processing of your Personal Information; the right to have your Personal Information transferred to another controller; the right to withdraw consent; and the right to lodge complaints with supervisory authorities. We may require proof of or need to verify your identity before we can give effect to these rights.

**Other Terms and Conditions:**

Your access to and use of the Services is subject to the Terms of Service.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy:**

The Services and our business may change from time to time. As a result, at times it may be necessary for us to make changes to this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time (collectively, "Modifications"). Modifications to this Privacy Policy will be posted to the FilmFreeway website with a change to the "Last Updated" date at the top of this Privacy Policy. In certain circumstances FilmFreeway may, but need not, provide you with additional notice of such Modifications, such as via email or with in-Service notifications. Modifications will be effective 30 days following the "Last Updated" date or such other date as communicated in any other notice to you. Please review this policy periodically, and especially before you provide any Personal Data. This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date indicated above. Your continued use of the Services following the effectiveness of any Modifications to this Privacy Policy constitutes acceptance of those Modifications. If any Modification to this Privacy Policy is not acceptable to you, your sole remedy is to cease accessing, browsing and otherwise using the Services.

**Access to Information:**

Festivals may access and update their Personal Data being stored by us by logging in and visiting the My Account page. Filmmaker and Festivals may also contact us directly at the address specified below with respect to Personal Data that is not accessible through the My Account page. We will take reasonable steps to respond to requests relating to Personal Data within 30 days, however, we may reject requests that we find to be unreasonable (i.e., require disproportionate efforts or material changes to our information systems), impractical or abusive (i.e., repetitive requests, requests made in bad faith, requests that would compromise third party information). Note that you may not have access to or the ability to update Non-Personal Data, much of which is held in aggregate form.

**Retention and Deletion:**

We may retain your Personal Data as long as you continue to use the Services. You may close your account by contacting us. However, we may retain Personal Data and Non-Personal Data for an additional period as is permitted or required under applicable laws. Even if we delete your Personal Data it may persist on backup or archival media and other information systems.

**Contacting FilmFreeway:**

Please also feel free to contact us if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our information practices. You may contact us by writing to https://filmfreeway.com/pages/contact.

If you have a complaint about FilmFreeway's privacy practices you should write to us at: FilmFreeway, 500-666 Burrard Street, Vancouver, BC, V6C 3P6, Canada, or by email to [support@filmfreeway.com](mailto:support@filmfreeway.com). We will take reasonable steps to work with you to attempt to resolve your complaint.

If you are an EU resident, you may contact our Data Protection Officer at dpo@filmfreeway.com

**Our Cookie Policy:**

This Cookie Policy sets forth our policy with respect to information, including personally identifiable information ("Personal Data"), that is collected from users of and/or visitors to the Services (including through those users' and visitors' agents) ("you" or "your"), through cookies, pixel tags, local shared objects, web storage and other similar technologies.

Please also refer to our Privacy Policy, into which this Cookie Policy is incorporated by reference, which sets forth our policy with respect to the collection, use, disclosure, transfer and storage of information, including Personal Data, that is collected from users of and/or visitors to the Services.

If you have any questions or concerns, please do not hesitate to contact us by using the following link: https://filmfreeway.com/pages/contact

**Consent:**

By using the Services, you are consenting to the use of the technologies described in this Cookie Policy to collect both Personal Data and non Personal Data and to the storage of information on your device or web browser as described herein.

What are cookies, pixel tags (aka clear GIFs or web beacons), local shared objects and web storage?

**1\. Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of information that is placed on your web browser when you access and/or use the Services that stores text and which can later be read back by the Services or third parties. They are used to recognize your browser.

**2\. Pixel Tags (aka Clear GIFs or Web Beacons)**

A pixel tag is a tiny invisible tag or graphic placed on certain parts of the Services, in emails or in certain other downloadable content, but not on your computer, mobile device or browser.

**3\. Local Shared Objects (aka Flash Cookies)**

A local shared object is similar to a cookie, except it is stored on your computer or mobile device, instead of your browser, and it can store more than just text. The methods for controlling local shared objects are different than the methods for controlling cookies (as discussed below).

**4\. Web Storage (aka HTML5 Local Storage)**

Web storage methods are similar to cookies but can store more information than cookies and usually store that information on a persistent basis.

**How can I manage these technologies?**

**1\. Cookies**

Cookies may be session cookies (i.e., last only for one browser session) or persistent cookies (i.e., continue in your browser until they are affirmatively deleted). You can manage cookies through your web browser's option settings and through those settings you may be able (i) to receive notifications when you are receiving new cookies, (ii) to disable cookies or (iii) to delete cookies. Please refer to your web browser's help section for information on how to do this.

**2\. Pixel Tags**

Pixel tags do not store information on your computer, mobile device or browser (although they are occasionally downloaded to your computer if contained in an email or other downloadable content) so cannot be managed by you.

**3\. Local Shared Objects**

Local shared objects are stored on your computer or mobile device. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for local shared objects, click here.

**4\. Web Storage**

Web Storage, or HTML5 Local Storage, is an industry-standard data storage technology that is implemented by browser manufacturers. Refer to your browser's help contents for procedures on how to manage settings for Web Storage.

**What do you use these technologies for?**

Generally we use these technologies for one of the following reasons:

**1\. Essential (strictly necessary)**

We use these technologies in a way that is essential for the operation of our Services or parts thereof. For example, we may use cookies to determine where to route your traffic to effectively distribute the workload across numerous computers.

**2\. Performance/Analytics**

We use these technologies to analyze how you use our Services and to monitor our Services. For example, we may place cookies that allow us (i) to measure the time of your requests to our servers and our responses, (ii) to A/B test new features, (iii) to record statistics about site usage, (iv) to track your activities on the Services, and (v) to track the places from which you come to the Services.

**3\. Functionality**

We use these technologies to allow us to provide certain functionality on the Services and to remember your preferences. For instance, when you click the "remember me" box on our log in page we place a persistent cookie on your browser that allows our Services to pre-populate your email address when you return. Other examples include remembering your preferences, preventing web application vulnerabilities, allowing for third party integrations, and in connection with providing search results.

**Does anybody else use these technologies on your Services?**

Most of the cookies and other technologies described above on our Services are set by us (aka first party cookies) or are used in connection with the Services and set by third party service providers at our direction ("Third Party Cookies"). We may use Third Party Cookies with respect to each of the uses set forth above. For example, we use technologies from Google Analytics to measure performance/analytics.
